GABRIELLE WALD

(617) 413-0253 • Email: gabibmello@gmail.com • LinkedIn: gabriellewald • GitHub: gabriellewald

SUMMARY

Data Scientist interested in surfacing insights from data. Experience creating accessible visualizations and predictive models for a wide range of applications. Passionate about the scientific method and the use of technology to generate positive impact, improve services, and uncover possible solutions.

SKILLS

- Programming: Python, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, sklearn, statsmodel, seaborn, jupyter notebook
- Descriptive and Inferential Statistics: p-value, test for significance (z-test, t-test, chi-squared, ANOVA)
- Experimental Design: A/B testing, hypothesis testing, confidence level
- Predictive Modeling: linear regression, logistic regression, classification, clustering, decision trees, random forest
- Data Science Methods: mining, wrangling, cleaning, analysis, visualization, storytelling
- Version Control: git, github
- Databases: SQL

PROJECT

Passing the Standards Projection

May 2021

Exploratory Data Analysis

- This project was an in-depth investigation of factors possibly affecting school performance
- Designed predictive model to project the percentage of students passing standard tests in CA K-12 public schools
- Modeled training data with several regression algorithms: linear regression, logistic regression, decision tree, random forest, lasso, and PCA
- Created unique dataset with test scores, financial investment in education, and several demographics regarding students and their families

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow, Springboard School of Data

Aug 2020 - Present

550+ hours of hands-on coursework, with 1:1 industry expert mentorship

- Created predictive model to understand student performance in CA K-12 public schools
- Formulated and tested hypotheses to understand demographic factors in performance
- Found and transformed several files to construct unique datasets
- Used machine learning algorithms in classification and regression models

Data Science Fellow, DS4A Empowerment Program | Correlation One

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

Merit-based fellowship with 5% acceptance rate led by Harvard Prof. Natesh Pillai

- Co-created capstone project to understand financial impact in CA K-12 public schools
- Ran regression models to determine variables of impact and identify confounding factors
- Performed t-test and chi-square analysis for hypothesis testing
- Conducted exploratory data analysis and created meaningful plots to identify patterns

Research Data Analyst, SELF-lab | UC Davis

May 2019 - Jul 2020

- Ran descriptives and constructed visualization for research in collaboration with the World Bank
- Organized and cleaned data with over 63,000 data points in R / Excel to prepare data for analysis
- Collaborated with researchers and participated in planning meetings

Research Assistant, Oakes Lab | Center for Mind and Brain

Aug 2018 – Jul 2019

- Ran eye-tracking software SMI, collected and coded infant behavior data
- Screened participants and followed IRB guidelines for research projects
- Trained new RAs on lab procedures and collaborated with the research team

Research Assistant, Rivera Lab | Center for Mind and Brain

Aug 2017 – Oct 2018

- Carried out data collection for behavioral studies
- Administered eye-tracking to study subjects

• Collaborated with P.I., PhD students, and fellow researchers

Vice President of Scholarship, PTK Honor Society International

- Partnered with organizations for collaboration on campus projects
- Led weekly meetings with society members to address action items
- Organized and presented induction ceremony to welcome new inductees

EDUCATION

University of California Davis

2017 - 2020

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

- Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Science, 3.65 GPA
- Computer Science and Neuroscience emphasis
- Relevant coursework: Applied Statistics, Biostatistics, Statistical Analysis in R, Linear Algebra, Research Methods, Data Structures and Algorithms in Python, Object Oriented Programming in Python

University of Hawaii | Kapiolani Community College

2013 - 2015

- Associate of Arts in Liberal Arts, 4.0 GPA Valedictorian
- Applied Linguistics Concentration
- Leadership: Vice President of Scholarship at Phi Theta Kappa Alpha Kappa Psi Chapter